Morris, James O. Collection of Labor Related Tape Recordings 5518 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
James O. Morris Collection of Labor Related Tape Recordings
1960-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Morris, James O.
5518 AV
1.17 cubic feet
1.2 linear ft.
Audio cassette tapes, open-reel audio tapes, pamphlets.
Collection consists of 10 audio reels and 1 cassette tape, collected by James Morris.
5658983
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 10, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 10, 2015
Scope and Contents
1-Agricultural organizing, 2-Emma Goldman, 3-Folklore of the American Labor Movement, 4-Man from Terre Haute and His Cause, Eugene Debs, 5-Norman Thomas & Eugene Debs 6-San Francisco Waterfront and General Strike pt.1, 7-pt.2, 8-She also ran-Victoria Woodhull, 9-What ever became-Warren K. Billings, 10-When labor was a dirty word
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3018: James O. Morris Papers /4055: James O. Morris Office Files /4056: James O. Morris Papers /4073: James O. Morris Office Files
Labor movement -- United States.; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Green, Archie; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855- 1926; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Woodhull, Victoria C. (Victoria Claflin), 1838-1927; Billings, Warren K., 1893-1972; Lamparski, Richard.; National Farm Workers Association
5658983
- On Agricultural Organizing, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  1 of 10
- Emma Goldman (Box 1, Folder 2)
  2 of 10
- Folklore of the American Labor Movement (Box 1, Folder 3)
  3 of 10
- Howard Hamilton & EV Debs: The Man from Terre Haute & His Cause (Eugene V. Debs) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  4 of 10
- Norman Thomas on Eugene Debs, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  5 of 10
- San Francisco Waterfront & General Strike, Part 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  6 of 10
- San Francisco Waterfront & General Strike, Part II (Box 1, Folder 7)
  7 of 10
- She also Ran-Victoria Woodhull (Box 1, Folder 8)
  8 of 10
- What Ever Became of Warren K. Billings, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  9 of 10
- When Labor War a Dirty Word, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  10 of 10
- Supplementary booklets for audio cassettes, boxes 3,4,5,6 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  bx 3-The Growth of American Trade Unions, the Policies of the American Federation of Labor / The Growth of American Trade Unions the Impact of Industrial Unionism; bx4-The New Deal and the Domestic Party / The New Deal and its Effects on Foreign Policy; bx5-Parties, Patronage and the Political - Machines in America / The New Politics; bx6-American Politics in the Age of Jackson - Parties and Sections in the 1820's / American Politics in the Age of Jackson - Whigs and Democrats in the 1830's
- Ben Albert, Director of Public Relations of COPE, Gregory Brewer, Prof. Morris (was removed from /4073 and placed in this collection) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Growth of American Trade Unions the Policies of the American Federation of Labor / The Growth of American Trade Unions the Impact of Industrial Unionism (Box 3, Folder 1)
- The New Deal and the Domestic Party / The New Deal and its Effects on Foreign Policy (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Parties, Patronage and the Political - Machines in America / The New Politics (Box 5, Folder 1)
- American Politics in the Age of Jackson - Parties and Sections in the 1820's / American Politics in the Age of Jackson - Whigs and Democrats in the 1830's (Box 6, Folder 1)
- The Man From Terre Haute & His Cause. Speakers: Howard Hamilton & Eugene Debs (Box 7, Folder 1)